export const chapter = "Chapter - 1: History : When, Where and How ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Who is often referred to as the 'Father of History'?",
        optionA: "Aristotle",
        optionB: "Herodotus",
        optionC: "Socrates",
        correctAnswer: "Herodotus",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the study or investigation of the past called according to Herodotus?",
        optionA: "Historiography",
        optionB: "History",
        optionC: "Anthropology",
        correctAnswer: "History",
      },
      {
        question: "Why do we study history?",
        optionA: "To predict the future",
        optionB: "To understand our present-day problems",
        optionC: "To learn about fictional stories",
        correctAnswer: "To understand our present-day problems",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the basis for marking years as BC or AD?",
        optionA: "Birth of a famous leader",
        optionB: "Birth of Lord Jesus",
        optionC: "Discovery of the printing press",
        correctAnswer: "Birth of Lord Jesus",
      },
      {
        question:
          "If India gained independence in 1947 AD, how long ago did it happen from the present year 2023 AD?",
        optionA: "1947 years ago",
        optionB: "76 years ago",
        optionC: "76 BC",
        correctAnswer: "76 years ago",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which geographical region is referred to as the Indian Subcontinent in the text?",
        optionA: "Present-day India only",
        optionB: "India, Pakistan, Afghanistan, Nepal, Bangladesh, and Bhutan",
        optionC: "Entire South Asia",
        correctAnswer:
          "India, Pakistan, Afghanistan, Nepal, Bangladesh, and Bhutan",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Why did civilizations often develop near rivers, according to the text?",
        optionA: "Rivers were a source of entertainment",
        optionB: "Rivers provided fertile land and abundant water resources",
        optionC: "Rivers had the best fishing spots",
        correctAnswer:
          "Rivers provided fertile land and abundant water resources",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which major empire developed along the banks of the River Ganga?",
        optionA: "Maurya Empire",
        optionB: "Gupta Empire",
        optionC: "Magadha Empire",
        correctAnswer: "Magadha Empire",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is one way people from different places interacted in the past?",
        optionA: "Through social media",
        optionB: "Through caravans and trade",
        optionC: "Through isolation",
        correctAnswer: "Through caravans and trade",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What knowledge spread from India to European countries through interaction, as mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "The concept of zero and decimal",
        optionB: "The art of war",
        optionC: "The art of cooking",
        correctAnswer: "The concept of zero and decimal",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Herodotus, a Greek historian, is often called the 'Father of History' because he is credited with pioneering the field of _______.",
        options: {
          optionA: "Geology",
          optionB: "Historiography",
          optionC: "Astrology",
        },
        correctAnswer: "Historiography",
      },
      {
        question:
          "History is the study of the past, which allows us to understand our _______ problems and how to tackle them effectively.",
        options: {
          optionA: "Current-day",
          optionB: "Future",
          optionC: "Past",
        },
        correctAnswer: "Current-day",
      },
      {
        question:
          "BC and AD are used to mark years based on the birth of Lord Jesus. BC stands for 'Before Christ,' and AD stands for 'Anno Domini,' which means 'Year of Our Lord.' For example, 2021 AD refers to the year that occurred 2021 years _______ this base year.",
        options: {
          optionA: "After",
          optionB: "Before",
          optionC: "During",
        },
        correctAnswer: "After",
      },
      {
        question:
          "India's territory in ancient times comprised present-day India, Pakistan, Afghanistan, Nepal, Bangladesh, and Bhutan, which together were known as _______.",
        options: {
          optionA: "Indian Confederation",
          optionB: "Greater India",
          optionC: "Indian Empire",
        },
        correctAnswer: "Greater India",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Different landforms in the Indian subcontinent, such as high and low hills, plains, deserts, and plateaus, influenced people's _______ , customs, and lifestyles.",
        options: {
          optionA: "Crops",
          optionB: "Foods",
          optionC: "Traditions",
        },
        correctAnswer: "Foods",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Major cities developed along the banks of the River Ganga nearly 2,500 years ago, and one of the most powerful empires that emerged in this region was _______.",
        options: {
          optionA: "Maurya",
          optionB: "Gupta",
          optionC: "Magadha",
        },
        correctAnswer: "Magadha",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Archaeological sources include evidences other than writings, such as monuments, artifacts, human remains, edicts, inscriptions, coins, jewelry, weapons, pottery, and metalware. Edicts and inscriptions are messages from ancient rulers engraved on pillars, walls, rocks, or metal plates, which provide insights into values, cultures, armies, religions, and social structure of ancient times. The Ashokan edict is one of the best examples of _______.",
        options: {
          optionA: "Sculpture",
          optionB: "Inscription",
          optionC: "Painting",
        },
        correctAnswer: "Inscription",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Monuments, such as temples, palaces, and forts built during ancient times, serve as evidence of excellent _______ and architectural knowledge of the past.",
        options: {
          optionA: "Cuisine",
          optionB: "Craftsmanship",
          optionC: "Geography",
        },
        correctAnswer: "Craftsmanship",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Artifacts excavated from different places, including paintings, sculptures, textiles, coins, jewelry, pottery, and metalware, provide insights into various aspects of the past, such as _______ and traditions.",
        options: {
          optionA: "Religions",
          optionB: "Crops",
          optionC: "Weapons",
        },
        correctAnswer: "Religions",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Coins found in archaeological excavations not only reveal trade between different places and countries but also showcase the development of _______ and technology in the past.",
        options: {
          optionA: "Mathematics",
          optionB: "Science",
          optionC: "Timekeeping",
        },
        correctAnswer: "Science",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Herodotus, a Greek historian, is often called the 'Father of History' because he is credited with pioneering the field of _______.",
        options: {
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "History is the study of the past, which allows us to understand our _______ problems and how to tackle them effectively.",
        options: {
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "BC and AD are used to mark years based on the birth of Lord Jesus. BC stands for 'Before Christ,' and AD stands for 'Anno Domini,' which means 'Year of Our Lord.' For example, 2021 AD refers to the year that occurred 2021 years _______ this base year.",
        options: {
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "India's territory in ancient times comprised present-day India, Pakistan, Afghanistan, Nepal, Bangladesh, and Bhutan, which together were known as _______.",
        options: {
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Different landforms in the Indian subcontinent, such as high and low hills, plains, deserts, and plateaus, influenced people's _______ , customs, and lifestyles.",
        options: {
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Major cities developed along the banks of the River Ganga nearly 2,500 years ago, and one of the most powerful empires that emerged in this region was _______.",
        options: {
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Archaeological sources include evidences other than writings, such as monuments, artifacts, human remains, edicts, inscriptions, coins, jewelry, weapons, pottery, and metalware. Edicts and inscriptions are messages from ancient rulers engraved on pillars, walls, rocks, or metal plates, which provide insights into values, cultures, armies, religions, and social structure of ancient times. The Ashokan edict is one of the best examples of _______.",
        options: {
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Monuments, such as temples, palaces, and forts built during ancient times, serve as evidence of excellent _______ and architectural knowledge of the past.",
        options: {
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Artifacts excavated from different places, including paintings, sculptures, textiles, coins, jewelry, pottery, and metalware, provide insights into various aspects of the past, such as _______ and traditions.",
        options: {
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Coins found in archaeological excavations not only reveal trade between different places and countries but also showcase the development of _______ and technology in the past.",
        options: {
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
